# Owen Adrian

Software developer with seven years of experience developing web applications and a passion for delivering value with secure software solutions. An immersive problem solver with an entrepreneurial focus on providing quality and consistency.

Mesa, AZ · (816) 944-0745 · me@owen.codes · owen.codes

### **Technical Skills**

- Languages: C#, Ruby, JavaScript, Python, HTML/CSS, Bash

- Frameworks: React, Svelte, Express.js, Ruby on Rails, ASP.NET Core

- **Databases:** PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB

Cloud Platforms: Azure (App Service, Kubernetes), AWS (EC2, S3)

- Tools: Git, Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, Heroku, CI/CD

## Experience

Software Consultant

Syntreno

Jul 2023 - Present

Developed and licensed an autonomous LLM agent written with C#.

**Full Stack Developer** 

VisualLive

Mar 2020 - Jun 2023

- Maintained a Ruby on Rails codebase and managed resources on Azure, driving the growth of a global leader in 3D visualization and collaboration in AEC.
- Provided subject-matter expertise and developed custom implementations for clients and Salesforce and Bitrix24 integrations for marketing and sales teams.
- Sped up model transformation tasks by 90% by deploying a containerized microservice in Ruby and C++, resulting in hours of gained productivity.
- Developed a custom data streaming protocol based on UDP that sent fragments of a memory-mapped 3D model to a viewer, reducing buffer times by 2 minutes.
- Deployed a Ruby on Rails monolith using Docker and documented deployment steps for on-premise support, enabling adoption by the US Army Corps of Engineers for the reconstruction of Tyndall Air Force Base.

## Web Developer, Founder

Order Coffee Online

September 2017 - Mar 2020

- Developed an online ordering system in Ruby on Rails that processed over \$500,000 in sales from 3 cafes and made the mornings of over 3,000 customers.
- Led every stage of SDLC from conceptualization to commercialization, refined project goals with product feedback, and developed marketing strategies.

### Education

**Technology Solutions** Northland Career and Professional Studies May 2018

High School Diploma Liberty North High School May 2018